{
  "allQuestions": [
    {
      "question": "What is the name of Thor’s hammer?",
      "answer": ["Norn", "Vanir", "Mjolnir", "Aesir"],
      "correctAnswer": "Mjolnir"
    },
    {
      "question": "What year was the first Iron Man movie released, kicking off the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
      "answer": ["2012", "2008", "2005", "2010"],
      "correctAnswer": "2008"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of doctor is Stephen Strange?",
      "answer": [
        "Trauma Surgeon",
        "Plastic Surgeon",
        "Neurosurgeon",
        "Cardiothoracic Surgeon"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Neurosurgeon"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Captain America’s shield made of?",
      "answer": ["Vibranium", "Carbonadium", "Adamantium", "Promethium"],
      "correctAnswer": "Vibranium"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the Incredible Hulk, what does Tony tell Thaddeus Ross at the end of the film?",
      "answer": [
        "That he knows about S.H.I.E.L.D.",
        "That he wants to study The Hulk",
        "That they are putting a team together",
        "That he wants to study The Hulk"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "That they are putting a team together"
    },
    {
      "question": "The Flerkens are a race of extremely dangerous aliens that resembles what?",
      "answer": [
        "Cats",
        "Ducks",
        "Reptiles",
        "Raccoons"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Cats"
    },
    {
      "question": "Before becoming Vision, what is the name of Iron Man’s A.I. butler?",
      "answer": [
        "H.O.M.E.R.",
        "J.A.R.V.I.S.",
        "A.L.F.R.E.D.",
        "M.A.R.V.I.N."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "J.A.R.V.I.S."
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the real name of the Black Panther?",
      "answer": [
        "M’Baku",
        "N’Jobu",
        "N’Jadaka",
        "T’Challa"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "T’Challa"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the last holder of the Space Stone before Thanos claims it for his Infinity Gauntlet?",
      "answer": [
        "The Collector",
        "Thor",
        "Loki",
        "Tony Stark"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Loki"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the alien race Loki sends to invade Earth in The Avengers?",
      "answer": [
        "The Skrulls",
        "The Kree",
        "The Flerkens",
        "The Chitauri"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "The Chitauri"
    },
    {
      "question": "What fake name does Natasha use when she first meets Tony?",
      "answer": [
        "Natalia Romanoff",
        "Nicole Rohan",
        "Natalie Rushman",
        "Naya Rabe"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Natalie Rushman"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does Thor want another of when he’s in the diner?",
      "answer": [
        "A slice of pie",
        "A cup of coffee",
        "A pint of beer",
        "A stack of pancakes"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "A cup of coffee"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where does Peggy tell Steve she wants to meet him for a dance, before he plunges into the ice?",
      "answer": [
        "El Morocco",
        "The Copacabana",
        "El Morocco",
        "The Stork Club"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "The Stork Club"
    },
    {
      "question": "About which city do Hawkeye and Black Widow often reminisce?",
      "answer": [
        "Prague",
        "Sokovia",
        "Istanbul",
        "Budapest"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Budapest"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who does the Mad Titan sacrifice to acquire the Soul Stone?",
      "answer": [
        "Cull Obsidian",
        "Nebula",
        "Ebony Maw",
        "Naya Rabe"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Gamora"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the little boy Tony befriends while stranded in the Iron Man 3?",
      "answer": [
        "Holden",
        "Harley",
        "Henry",
        "Harry"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Harley"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where do Lady Sif and Volstagg keep the Reality Stone after the Dark Elves tried to steal it?",
      "answer": [
        "On Vormir",
        "Inside Sif’s sword",
        "In a vault on Asgard",
        "To the Collector"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "To the Collector"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the Winter Soldier say after Steve recognizes him for the first time?",
      "answer": [
        "'Who the hell is Bucky?'",
        "'He’s gone.'",
        "'What did you say?'",
        "'Do I know you?'"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "'Who the hell is Bucky?'"
    },
    {
      "question": "What were the three items Rocket claims he needs in order to escape the prison?",
      "answer": [
        "A pair of binoculars, a detonator, and a prosthetic leg",
        "A knife, cable wires, and Peter’s mixtape",
        "A security band, a battery, and a prosthetic leg",
        "A pair of binoculars, a detonator, and a prosthetic leg"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "A security band, a battery, and a prosthetic leg"
    },
    {
      "question": "What word does Tony utter that makes Steve say, “Language”?",
      "answer": [
        "'Idiot!'",
        "'Asshole!'",
        "'Crap'",
        "'Shit!'"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "'Shit!'"
    },
    {
      "question": "What animal does Darren Cross unsuccessfully shrink in the Ant-Man?",
      "answer": [
        "Sheep",
        "Duck",
        "Hamster",
        "Mouse"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Sheep"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is killed by Loki in the Avengers?",
      "answer": [
        "Agent Coulson",
        "Nick Fury",
        "Doctor Erik Selvig",
        "Maria Hill"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Agent Coulson"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is Black Panther’s sister?",
      "answer": [
        "Ramonda",
        "Okoye",
        "Shuri",
        "Nakia"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Shuri"
    },
    {
      "question": "What landmark does Peter Parker rescue his classmates from in Spider-Man: Homecoming?",
      "answer": [
        "Mount Rushmore",
        "Washington Monument",
        "Golden Gate Bridge",
        "Statue of Liberty"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Washington Monument"
    },
    {
      "question": "What song does Baby Groot dance to at the end of the first Guardian of the Galaxy?",
      "answer": [
        "‘Hooked On A Feeling’ – Voidoid",
        "‘I Want You Back’ – The Jackson 5",
        "‘Cherry Bomb’ – The Runaways",
        "‘Ain’t No Mountain High Enough’ – Marvin Gaye & Tammi Terrell"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "‘I Want You Back’ – The Jackson 5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who are the primordial beings that are responsible for the creation of the Infinity Stones?",
      "answer": [
        "Asgardians",
        "Frost Giants",
        "Cosmic Entities",
        "Korg"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Cosmic Entities"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Deadpool’s real name?",
      "answer": [
        "Wanda Maximoff",
        "Peter Parker",
        "Wade Wilson",
        "Tony Stark"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Wade Wilson"
    },
    {
      "question": "In ‘Black Panther’, what African country is Nakia operating in as a spy before T’Challa arrived and brought her back to Wakanda?",
      "answer": [
        "Ghana",
        "Nigeria",
        "Sokovia",
        "Wakanda"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Nigeria"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the villain of ‘Thor: The Dark World’?",
      "answer": [
        "Kaecilius",
        "Ghost",
        "Red Skull",
        "Malekith"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Malekith"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the infinity stones is hidden on Vormir?",
      "answer": [
        "Soul Stone",
        "Power Stone",
        "Reality Stone",
        "Time Stone"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Soul Stone"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the real name of the Scarlet Witch?",
      "answer": [
        "Peggy Carter",
        "Wanda Maximoff",
        "Carol Danvers",
        "Nebula"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Wanda Maximoff"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which film’s post-credit scene did Thanos first appear?",
      "answer": [
        "Guardians of the Galaxy",
        "The Avengers",
        "Avengers: Endgame",
        "Thor: Ragnarok"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "The Avengers"
    },
    {
      "question": "In ‘Doctor Strange’, the Time Stone is revealed to be hidden inside what artifact?",
      "answer": [
        "Crimson Bands Of Cyttorak",
        "Twilight Sword",
        "Wand Of Watoomb",
        "Eye of Agamotto"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Eye of Agamotto"
    },
    {
      "question": "What German airport does the clash of the Avengers take place?",
      "answer": [
        "Leipzig / Halle",
        "PIER 13",
        "DAIRY QUEEN",
        "XANDAR PLAZA"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Leipzig / Halle"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which planet does Peter Quill retrieve the Orb containing the Power Stone?",
      "answer": [
        "Morag",
        "Vanaheim",
        "Asgard",
        "Earth"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Morag"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who killed Tony Stark’s parents?",
      "answer": [
        "Whiplash",
        "Red Skull",
        "Carol Danvers",
        "The Winter Soldier"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "The Winter Soldier"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the mysterious glowing blue cube which Loki uses as a weapon?",
      "answer": [
        "The Darkhold",
        "Infinity Gauntlet",
        "The Tesseracts",
        "The Darkhold"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "The Tesseract"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who has directed the most MCU movies?",
      "answer": [
        "Peyton Ree",
        "The Russo Brothers",
        "Anthony and Joe Russo",
        "Jon Watts"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "The Russo Brothers"
    },
    {
      "question": "What Top Gun character is Captain America’s cat named after?",
      "answer": [
        "Goose",
        "Selmon",
        "Zack",
        "Gippy"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Goose"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the axe that is forged from the heat of a dying neutron star for Thor?",
      "answer": [
        "Hofund",
        "Godslayer",
        "Yaka Arrows",
        "Stormbreaker"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Stormbreaker"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which film did The Aether first appear in?",
      "answer": [
        "Avenger 1",
        "Thor: The Dark World",
        "Hulk",
        "Iron Man 1"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Thor: The Dark World"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many Infinity Stones are there?",
      "answer": [
        "5",
        "8",
        "4",
        "6"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "6"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the organisation revealed to have taken over S.H.I.E.L.D. in Captain America: The Winter Soldier?",
      "answer": [
        "Mirage",
        "Kree",
        "Hydra",
        "Area 51"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Goose"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the only Marvel film not to have a post-credit scene?",
      "answer": [
        "Avengers: Endgame",
        "Ant Man",
        "Thor: Ragnarok",
        "The Avengers"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Avengers: Endgame"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Iron Man 2 launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2014",
        "2015",
        "2010",
        "2013"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2010"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Iron Man launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2010",
        "2009",
        "2008",
        "2007"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2008"
    },
    {
      "question": "When The Incredible Hulk launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2010",
        "2008",
        "2009",
        "2006"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2008"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Marvel's The Avengers launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2011",
        "2010",
        "2013",
        "2012"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2012"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Thor launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2015",
        "2014",
        "2011",
        "2012"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2011"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Captain America: The First Avenger launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2013",
        "2015",
        "2012",
        "2011"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2011"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Iron Man 3 launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2014",
        "2016",
        "2013",
        "2010"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2013"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Ant-Man launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2014",
        "2015",
        "2012",
        "2016"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2015"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Captain America: The Winter Soldier launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2015",
        "2016",
        "2017",
        "2014"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2014"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Thor: The Dark World launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2012",
        "2010",
        "2009",
        "2013"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2013"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Avengers: Age of Ultron World launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2012",
        "2015",
        "2011",
        "2013"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2015"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Guardians of the Galaxy launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2012",
        "2015",
        "2014",
        "2013"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2014"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Captain America: Civil War launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2012",
        "2015",
        "2014",
        "2016"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2016"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Doctor Strange launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2016",
        "2015",
        "2014",
        "2013"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2016"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2 launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2012",
        "2015",
        "2014",
        "2017"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2017"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Spider-Man: Homecoming launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2017",
        "2015",
        "2014",
        "2013"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2017"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Thor: Ragnarok launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2013",
        "2016",
        "2014",
        "2017"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2017"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Black Panther launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2020",
        "2017",
        "2018",
        "2019"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2018"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Avengers: Infinity War launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2018",
        "2019",
        "2016",
        "2020"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2018"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Ant-Man and the Wasp launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2021",
        "2018",
        "2016",
        "2019"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2018"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Captain Marvel launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2021",
        "2020",
        "2019",
        "2018"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2019"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Avengers: Endgame launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2018",
        "2021",
        "2020",
        "2019"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2019"
    },
    {
      "question": "When Spider-Man: Far From Home launched?",
      "answer": [
        "2017",
        "2019",
        "2020",
        "2021"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2019"
    },
    {
      "question": "Character name of “Hulk” ?",
      "answer": [
        "Clint Barton",
        "Sharon Carter",
        "Carol Danvers",
        "Bruce Banner"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Bruce Banner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Character name of “Winter Soldier” ?",
      "answer": [
        "Clint Barton",
        "James Bucky Barnes",
        "Tony Stark",
        "Bruce Banner"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Bruce Banner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Character name of “Star-Lord” ?",
      "answer": [
        "Tony Stark",
        "Sharon Carter",
        "Peter Quill",
        "Steve Rogers"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Peter Quill"
    },
    {
      "question": "Character name of “Captain America” ?",
      "answer": [
        "Clint Barton",
        "Sharon Carter",
        "James Rhodey Rhodes",
        "Steve Rogers"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Steve Rogers"
    },
    {
      "question": "Character name of “Iron Man” ?",
      "answer": [
        "Bruce Banner",
        "Tony Stark",
        "James Rhodey Rhodes",
        "Steve Rogers"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Tony Stark"
    },
    {
      "question": "Character name of “War Machine / Iron Patriot” ?",
      "answer": [
        "Bruce Banner",
        "J.A.R.V.I.S.",
        "James Rhodey Rhodes",
        "Taneleer Tivan"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "James Rhodey Rhodes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Character name of “Falcon” ?",
      "answer": [
        "Sam Wilson",
        "J.A.R.V.I.S.",
        "Stephen Strange",
        "Taneleer Tivan"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Sam Wilson"
    },
    {
      "question": "Character name of “Black Widow” ?",
      "answer": [
        "Sam Wilson",
        "Maggie",
        "Natasha Romanoff",
        "Carol Danvers"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Natasha Romanoff"
    },
    {
      "question": "Character name of “Collector” ?",
      "answer": [
        "Wong",
        "Erik Selvig",
        "Ronan the Accuser",
        "Taneleer Tivan"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Taneleer Tivan"
    },
    {
      "question": "The correct order of trigger words to activate Bucky Barne's brainwashing:",
      "answer": [
        "Longing, furnace, daybreak, rusted, seventeen,...",
        "Longing, rusted, furnace, daybreak, seventeen,...",
        "Longing, daybreak, furnace, seventeen, rusted,...",
        "Longing, rusted, daybreak, furnace, seventeen,..."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Longing, rusted, furnace, daybreak, seventeen,..."
    }
  ]
}
